{
    "id": "c64b3b319fa14304b3d7966d248ec187",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise (Intermediate)",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "c96c22fda04b42d5856bd78e0eabb92e",
            "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "She writes better ……………………. anybody I know.",
                    "description": "Better is a comparative word. It is followed by than.",
                    "answers": [
                        "than",
                        "compared to"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I have hardly been ………………………… since June.",
                    "description": "Non-assertive words like any, anywhere, anywhere are more common after negative expressions like hardly etc.",
                    "answers": [
                        "anywhere",
                        "somewhere"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I have …………………………. met the President.",
                    "description": "Never is used in statements. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "never",
                        "ever"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Have you …………………………….. spoken to them?",
                    "description": "Ever is used in questions. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "ever",
                        "never"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "It is difficult to understand ………………………… he says.",
                    "description": "Non-assertive words like anybody and anything are mainly used with words expressing a negative kind of meaning.",
                    "answers": [
                        "anything",
                        "something"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The doctors went on strike, but …………………………… the nurses.",
                    "description": "To make a word, expression or clause negative, we use not.",
                    "answers": [
                        "not",
                        "no",
                        "not any"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "…………………………. nurses went on strike.",
                    "description": "No can mean not any.",
                    "answers": [
                        "No",
                        "Not",
                        "Not any"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "…………………………… you say, I will always trust him.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "No matter what",
                        "Whatever",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "Wake me when you arrive, ………………………………. late it is.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "no matter how",
                        "however",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "She is ……………………….. a great singer than I am.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "no better",
                        "no more"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "It takes ……………………………. to get to her house.",
                    "description": "In affirmatives we usually use a long time. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "long",
                        "a long time"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "You look ………………………….. What is the matter?",
                    "description": "Look is a copular verb. It is followed by an adjective. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "angry",
                        "angrily",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}